# **NIRAV GANDHI**

[Sr. Front-end Developer/ Team Leader]

#### Address:

B-501, Swagat Blossom 3BHK, B/h Aashka Multispecialty Hospital, Gandhinagar By-pass Road, Sargasan, Gandhinagar – 382421.

**Phone:** +91 9979586348

Email: gandhi.nirav7751@gmail.com

Solution-driven professional excelling in highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused web sites using HTML, CSS, JQuery, PHP and JavaScript. Experience building products for desktop, phone and mobile app users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

# **Skills**

Skill	Ratings from 5
Web development projects	4
Software best practices	4
Node Js	4
Backbone js	5
React js	3
AWS	2
Action Script 3.0	3
PHP	3
HTML	5
SASS	3
Ruby On Rails	3

# **Work History**

## **Sr. Software Developer –** March 2017 to Present

3 Year & 10 Months

Syx Automations India Pvt. Ltd. Currently known as (Gantner Infotec India Pvt. Ltd.) (Gujarat – India)

- Joining in to team as and Senior Software Developer Frontend and later on my role had been updated to the Team Leader
- Working on the development of Two Main Web Application (i3Learnhub and i3Campfire).
- Created eye catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity.
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement.
- Created site layout and user interface using HTML and CSS practices.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Reviewed code to validate structures, assess security and verify browser, device and operating system compatibility.
- Deploy code over amazon cloud
- Git branch, versions, releases Management

#### **Team Leader – November 2013 to March 2017**

3 Year & 4 Months

Academy for Computer Training (Gujarat – India)

- Joining in to team as and Senior Software Developer Frontend and later on my role had been updated to the Team Leader
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for creating well-organized project plans.
- Consulted regularly with internal customers on application development project status, new project proposals and software-related technical issues.
- Created and implemented development strategies for impactful projects.
- Developed databases, programs and processes for integration and implementation across enterprise.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Used programming capabilities in PHP, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed.

#### **Software Engineer – November 2011 to July 2013**

1 Year & 9 Months

Azilen Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Ahmedabad (Gujarat – India)

- Working as a Flash Programmer.
- Working on the development of a touch-screen based Digital Menu-System.
- Main responsibilities include understanding and implement requirements of the system's front-end following stipulated deadlines.

#### Trainee – February 2011 to October 2011

#### 9 Months

Gateway Technolabs Pvt Ltd., Ahmedabad (Gujarat - India)

- Worked in a 3 Member Team as Team Lead in a project Event Management.
- Collect the requirement from project manager, create High level design document, manage the entire code and finalize the UI for the project.

## Education

**MCA (Master In Computer Application)** (June 2011)

LDRP Institute of Technology and Research, Ahmedabad (Gujarat – India)

First - Class (65.66%)

**BCOM (Bachelor In Commerce)** 

(March 2007)

Sardar Vallabhbhai College of Commerce, Ahmedabad (Gujarat – India)

**Second - Class (59.68%)** 

# **Projects**

i3Learnhub (Gantner Infotech India Pvt. Ltd.):

I3Learnhub is an interactive learning software which sold by client with i3Touch board. This project is widely used in Belgium countries for schools and colleges. It is a canvas based learning application which include following modules. Login, Signup, Payment using Paypal, Signup With Oauth, Collaboration, Interactive Canvas with some tools like (pens, shapes, Geometric equipments, etc.)

This software is already live so you can visit (https://www.i3learnhub.com/login)

**Skills Used:** JavaScript, Node js, Backbone Js, Kinetic Js, React Js, HTML, SAAS, Ruby On Rails, PostgresSql, AWS, i18n(Localization)

i3Campfire (Gantner Infotech India Pvt. Ltd.):

i3CAMPFIRE is a cloud based meeting platform that can be accessed anytime, anywhere and on any device. You can instantly connect to a shared whiteboard with any mobile device seamlessly from any location, whether it's in the meeting room or across the globe.

This software is already live so you can visit (https://app.i3campfire.com/login)

**Skills Used:** JavaScript, Node js, Backbone Js, Kinetic Js, HTML, SAAS, Ruby On Rails, PostgresSql, AWS, i18n

## Papyrus XT (Academy for Computer Training):

Papyrus xt is software for IIT Kharagpur In which no lab but it comes with digital classrooms in which all the activity digitally displayed in classroom. We are developing software which is integrated with their api. There are Patrons can interactively and adaptive English learning,

Skills Used: JavaScript, Node js, Backbonejs, HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap

### **Junior** (Academy for Computer Training):

Junior is software which specially designed for STD 3 to 12 students to learn English. Patrons can interactively and adaptive English learning. There are student progress report, adaptive learning with recording audio.

Skills Used: PHP, JavaScript, HTML 5, CSS3, Flash for recording and games.

### **Senior** (Academy for Computer Training):

Senior is software which specially designed for College students to learn English. Patrons can interactively and adaptive English learning. There are student progress report, adaptive learning with recording audio.

**Skills Used:** PHP, JavaScript, HTML 5, CSS3, Flash for recording and games.

#### Words worth CPanel (Academy for Computer Training):

Cpanel is software is specially designed for managing our licensing and sites and manages our all schools and collages data.

Skills Used: PHP Laravel, JavaScript, HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap.

## **MOSAIC** (Academy for Computer Training):

MOSAIC Server is software is designed our whole content dynamically and remove php with nodejs and mongo db.

MOSAIC Client is designed for all platforms and automatically connects with mosaic server and displays its content from server.

Skills Used: NodeJS, Mongo DB, HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and Cordova for Mobile Platform.

## EMenu (Azilen Technologies Pvt. Ltd.):

Emenu is a touch-based digital menu that can be used as a substitute of traditional printed menus in restaurants, hotels and multiplex theaters. Patrons can interactively navigate food-items and place order through this application that runs on a mobile device like a tablet or a smart-phone. The order is directly received and processed at the order-desk and kitchen.

**Skills Used:** Flash, Action Script – 3, Air 2.5.

#### **Event Management** (Gateway Technolabs Pvt. Ltd.):

It is a web application aimed to assist in event management for an organization.

**Skills Used:** JSP, Struts, HTML5, MySQL, and CSS.